https://www.lighthouseguild.org/privacy-policy/donor-privacy-policy/

Donor Privacy Policy Purpose of Policy
Lighthouse Guild values each donor and is committed to protecting their privacy. The purpose of this Policy is to provide transparency as to Lighthouse Guild’s practices, policies, and procedures for the collection, use, and protection of Personally Identifiable Information (PII) relating to donors and prospective donors.
Scope
Lighthouse Guild protects PII in compliance with the HIPAA Privacy and Security regulations. All donors who submit PII to Lighthouse Guild must consent to the terms and conditions of the policy and to our processing and use of PII for the purposes stated below.
Statement of Policy
Donor information is used by Lighthouse Guild for charitable purposes only. Names, addresses and any other personal data provided by donors will be used to keep donors informed of our activities, programs, special events, and funding needs. If at any time a donor chooses not to receive these communications, they may contact Lighthouse Guild to remove their name from the mailing list.
Use of Personal Information. Lighthouse Guild may collect and maintain donor names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and some billing information in order to process electronic payments and event registrations. We may also verify with third parties the payment information collected in the course of processing a gift, donation, or registration. Donor information is maintained in a secured database, and only authorized personnel have access to the information and only for appropriate business purposes.
Protection of Donor Information. In accordance with the guidelines and best practices outlined by the Association of Fundraising Professionals and the Direct Marketing Association and the HIPAA Security Rule, Lighthouse Guild employs physical and technical safeguards to protect PII. Lighthouse Guild only retains the names and contact information for its donors in its database. Donors have the right to review personal information collected by Lighthouse Guild and to request their information be removed from our mailing list or any mailing list that we may share with other organizations for direct marketing purposes.
To review personal information or remove your name from our list, please contact the Development Department at 646-874-8219 or development@lighthouseguild.org.
Authorized Release of Information. Lighthouse Guild may be legally required to disclose personal information on occasion. Lighthouse Guild complies with all applicable legal requirements and standards.
